[
  {
    "question": "Neptune has __________ number of moons.",
    "options": [
      "15",
      "14",
      "11"
    ],
    "correct": "14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neptune was first observed by  __________.",
    "options": [
      "William Hershel",
      "Urbain Le Verrier & Johann Galle",
      "Galileo Galilei"
    ],
    "correct": "Urbain Le Verrier & Johann Galle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is one of Neptuneâ€™s moons?",
    "options": [
      "Ariel",
      "Triton",
      "Titan"
    ],
    "correct": "Triton"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the temperature on the surface of Neptune?",
    "options": [
      "-218C",
      "-214C",
      "-213C"
    ],
    "correct": "-214C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of spacecrafts that have visited Neptune is _________.",
    "options": [
      "3",
      "1",
      "2"
    ],
    "correct": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the approximate value of polar diameter of Neptune?",
    "options": [
      "48,000-49,000 km",
      "45,000-46,000 km",
      "40,000-41,000 km"
    ],
    "correct": "48,000-49,000 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neptune orbits the Sun once every _______ Earth years.",
    "options": [
      "145.9",
      "150.2",
      "164.8"
    ],
    "correct": "164.8"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was Neptune discovered?",
    "options": [
      "June 16th, 1846",
      "September 23rd, 1846",
      "May 19th, 1846"
    ],
    "correct": "September 23rd, 1846"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mass of Neptune?",
    "options": [
      "10^26 kg",
      "10^25 kg",
      "10^24 kg"
    ],
    "correct": "10^26 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neptune has _________ rings.",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "8",
      "12"
    ],
    "correct": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance of the orbit of Neptune is approximately _____________.",
    "options": [
      "4,590,000,000 km",
      "4,780,000,000 km",
      "4,498,000,000 km"
    ],
    "correct": "4,498,000,000 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neptune takes ________ hours to complete one rotation on its axis.",
    "options": [
      "15",
      "19",
      "18"
    ],
    "correct": "18"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inner core of Neptune is made up of __________.",
    "options": [
      "Rock",
      "Magma",
      "Metal"
    ],
    "correct": "Rock"
  },
  {
    "question": "The atmosphere of Neptune is made up of _____________.",
    "options": [
      "Hydrogen, helium and argon",
      "Methane, helium and argon",
      "Hydrogen, helium and methane"
    ],
    "correct": "Hydrogen, helium and methane"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neptune has a mass __________ that of Uranus.",
    "options": [
      "Greater than",
      "Lesser than",
      "Equal to"
    ],
    "correct": "Greater than"
  }
]